# **Ahmad Ali**

Full-stack Developer - London, UK. Portfolio: https://ahmad-ali.co.uk/

Email: ahmad.ali.uk14@gmail.com • phone: 07383164194 • GitHub: https://github.com/ahmad-ali14

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmad-ali-07383164194/

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a software engineer. I assist in teaching 8-months full-stack course at CodeYourFuture. My background is in pharmacy and analytical chemistry which I studied for 5 years and practised for 2 years. I finished more than 35 online courses around coding. I'm currently studying computer science at UoPeople university.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Upwork**, London— Freelance Full-stack Developer

Oct 2020 - PRESENT

- Developed, Designed and Deployed websites and online shops for clients.
- Maintained responsive products with security standards and basic SEO.
- Directly dealt with clients and adjust products according to their needs.
- Provided technical training and after-sale support to my clients.

# **Code Your Future,** London— Full Stack Developer

**April 2020 - PRESENT** 

- Full teaching day each Sunday, 8 months course long.
- Lead 3 graduates on their final project.
- Mentor 3 students directly throughout the course duration.
- Assist maintaining the school tech infrastructure.
- Stack: JS: React, Redux, Node, MongoDB, Docker, AWS, CircleCl
- This is a volunteering position.

# **Pharmacist**, Syria— Baylasan Pharmacy

Nov 2016 - April 2018

- Registered prescribing pharmacist. Community pharmacist and medical representative.

#### **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

- I Believe In Science, Lebanon - Science Translator Arabic / English 2018 - 2019

- MW-LABS, Syria - Freelance Social Media Marketer 2014 - 2016

#### **SKILLS**

- Js/Ts, React-Node, MongoDB, MySQL, Html, CSS, bootstrap, jquery
- Rest API, git, npm, Docker, Php, WordPress, WP API.
- Sequalize, Formik, Material UI, Redux, Redux sagas, Golang, Python, Heroku, stripe, GoCardless, AWS ...
- Responsive web design, eCommerce, money-handlers integration.

## **PROJECTS**

- Hex Luxury LTD April 2020 <a href="https://hexltd.co/">https://hexltd.co/</a>
- Roye Interiors LTD December 2019 <a href="https://royeinteriors.com/">https://royeinteriors.com/</a>
- **Lesvos Forms** September 2020 <a href="https://central.ahmad-ali.co.uk/">https://central.ahmad-ali.co.uk/</a> (demo)
- Bike Change Guru September 2020 <a href="https://www.bikechange.guru/">https://www.bikechange.guru/</a>
- Code Your Future April 2020 <a href="https://codevourfuture.io/">https://codevourfuture.io/</a>

Details and other projects are on my website <a href="https://www.ahmad-ali.co.uk/projects">https://www.ahmad-ali.co.uk/projects</a>

#### **EDUCATION**

University of The People, USA — Bachelor Computer Science 2020 - 2023 (exp)

- Online, part-time. Some courses: programming1(python), programming2(java).

# **Kiron Open Higher Education,** Germany — Associate Degree in Computer Science **2018 - 2020**

- Give their students access to online courses, which I finished 35 of 100 courses.
- More here: https://kiron.ngo/en/about-us/

# Free Code Camp, Online — Full Stack Developer BootCamp 2019

- More here: <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn">https://www.freecodecamp.org/learn</a>

**Damascus University,** Syria — Bachelor degree in pharmacy and pharmaceutical chemistry **2011-2016** 

- Some courses: analytical chemistry 1-2-3, biotechnology 1-2, bioinformatics ...

## **RECENT ONLINE LEARNING**

- Introduction to Software Product Management, University of Alberta Coursera.
- Algorithmic Toolbox and data structures, University of California San Diego Coursera
- List of all courses here: <a href="https://www.ahmad-ali.co.uk/#online-education">https://www.ahmad-ali.co.uk/#online-education</a>